userbenchmark.com 2019-08-28

# UserBenchmark Privacy Policy - UserBenchmark

## Terms And Conditions

The UserBenchmark website is a free service that is provided “AS IS”. Although the ambition is to have top quality performance and information at all times, UserBenchmark provides no warranties whatsoever regarding availability, server uptime or the accuracy of the information on the website. UserBenchmark is a way of finding hardware products that meet your specific criteria and by using the website you understand and agree to the fact that you are solely responsible for the consequences of using the website or its software to help formulate opinions. We encourage you to cross reference multiple sources prior to formulating opinions. If you have any questions or suggestions regarding this policy or anything else regarding UserBenchmark feel free to [contact us](mailto:support@userbenchmark.com) at any time.

* * *

## Privacy Policy

This privacy policy sets out how UserBenchmark uses and protects any information that you provide when you use this website or its software.

UserBenchmark is committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected. Should we ask you to provide certain information by which you can be identified when using this website or should you choose to download and run our software, then you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with this privacy statement.

UserBenchmark may change this policy by updating this page. You should check this page from time to time to ensure that you are happy with any changes. This policy is effective from 2014-09-21.

### What we collect

If you choose to create an account we will collect the following personally identifiable information:

  * Username
  * Email address and website url
  * Preferences and bio
  * Actions on UserBenchmark including comments, "likes" and user ratings
  * Profile picture

If you choose to download and run our software we will collect:

  * Anonymous hardware specifications and performance data from your PC

### What we do with the information we gather

We rely on legitimate interests as the legal basis to use this information to provide you with a better and more personalized service. This includes some or all of the following reasons:

  * To collect and present computer component performance statistics
  * To generate hardware rankings and recommendations
  * Anti-spam measures
  * Internal record keeping

* * *

### Security

We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorised access or disclosure we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect.

* * *

### Cookies

You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. This will prevent you from taking full advantage of the website.

Cookies on UserBenchmark are used in the following way:

  * Traffic log cookies identify which pages are being used. This helps us analyse data about web page traffic and improve our website in order to tailor it to your needs
  * To remember your login details (where you have created an account and chosen to auto login)
  * Third party vendors, including Google, use cookies to serve ads based on your prior visits to a website.

Overall, cookies help us provide you with a better website, by remembering your login details and by enabling us to monitor which pages you find useful and which you do not.

* * *

### Third Party Ads

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our website. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address, or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you.

Google's use of the DoubleClick cookie enables it and its partners to serve ads that are based on your visits to UserBenchmark and/or other sites across the Internet. Find out more about how Google manages data in its ads products [here](https://www.google.com/policies/technologies/partner-sites/). You can see and control what information Google use to show you ads by visiting [ad settings](https://adssettings.google.com/).

You can opt out of a third-party vendor's use of cookies for interest-based advertising by visiting [aboutads.info](http://www.aboutads.info/).

* * *

### Links to other websites

Our website may contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.

* * *

### Controlling your personal information

You may choose to restrict the collection or use of your personal information by browsing UserBenchmark without being signed into a personal user account and by not downloading and running our software.

We will not sell, distribute or lease your personal information to third parties unless we are required by law to do so.

If you believe that any information we are holding on you is incorrect or incomplete, please [email](mailto:support@userbenchmark.com) us as soon as possible and we will promptly update our records.
